Native American Women's Health Education Resource Center Records, 1986-2011
Sophia Smith Collection
- SERIES II. NATIVE AMERICAN COMMUNITY BOARD (NACB)
  - Financial materials
    - Tax exempt status 1986-87, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Balance sheet 1988, 1991-92 (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
    - Financial statements 1989-91, 1996-2003 (Box 2, Folder 3-4)
    - Annual Detail ledger 1991 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - General ledger, 30 Sep 1992 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Income tax forms 1989-2004 (Box 2, Folder 7-10)
    - Miscellaneous 1990-97 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Proposals and miscellaneous 1986-87 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- SERIES III. NAWHERC ADMINISTRATION
  - General 1990-93 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Advisory Committee 1991 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Calendars 1991-92 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence
    - General (Box 2)
      - 1987-89 (Box 2, Folder 16-17)
      - 1990-2006, undated (Box 3, Folder 1-6)
    - Andes Central School District 1988-89 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Boston Women's Health Book Collective 1988-96 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Senator Tom Daschle 1989-2003, nd. (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Sioux Falls Argus Leader 1988-89 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Yankton Sioux Tribe 1989-96, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Equipment inventory 1993 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Incident reports 1993-94 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Interns
    - General 1988-93, undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Orientation manual by Amy Maher, Oct 1992 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Job descriptions 1993, undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Office forms, undated (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Mailing lists 1999, undated (Box 3, Folder 18-19)
  - Meeting notes, miscellaneous 1991-93, 1996, undated (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
  - National Cancer Institute data collection, Cervical Cancer video for Native Americans 1991 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Notes, miscellaneous 1991, undated (Box 4, Folder 4-5)
  - Public Service Announcements 1996-99, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - South Dakota Touring Arts Teams visits to Lake Andes 1992-93 (Box 4, Folder 7-8)
  - Staff
    - General 1982-91 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Assignment sheets 1991-92 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Meeting minutes 1991-93 (Box 4, Folder 11-13)
    - Reports 1988-94 (Box 4, Folder 14-16)
    - Retreat 1994 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - University of South Dakota, Nutrition Consultant Services 1992, undated (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Valentine's Day Sobriety Dance, 14 Feb 1990 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Victims of Crime Assistance (VOCA) contract 1989 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Volunteers in Service to America (VISTA)
    - General 1993-94 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Orientation, May 1994 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Weekly visits and calls totals 1988-92 (Box 5, Folder 3-7)
  - The Winters Group, Women of Color Reproductive Health Care Study 1990-91, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Work notes 1994 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Workshop evaluations 1989 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- SERIES IV. FINANCIAL MATERIALS
  - General 1988-94, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Chart of Accounts 1993, undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Funding sources 1984, undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Kathleen Broken Rope Fund 1992, undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Funding correspondence
    - General 1988-95, undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Chief Illiniwek Education Foundation (CHIEF) controversy 1999 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Domestic and Sexual Abuse (DASA) grant 1993-94 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Funding Exchange, National Community Funds (Box 5)
      - 1987-88 (Box 5, Folder 18)
      - 1989-91 (Box 6, Folder 1-3)
    - Innovations in State and Local Government Program (Ford Foundation and Kennedy School of Government) 1990 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Joint Foundation Support, Inc. 1988-91 (Box 6, Folder 5-7)
    - Needmor Fund 1988-89 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Presbytery of the Northern Plains and Dakota Presbytery 1987-90 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Robert Wood Johnson Foundation 1988-91 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Ruth Mott Fund 1987-89 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Seventh Generation Fund 1988-90, undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - South Dakota Community Foundation 1988-90 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - South Dakota Department of Labor, Job Training Partnership Act 1990-92 (Box 6, Folder 14-15)
    - Lyn Stephens 1990-92 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Tides Foundation 1991-94 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - United Methodist Church 1988-89 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - United States Department of Health and Human Services, Office of Minority Health 1989 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Genevieve Vaughan 1988-90 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Victims of Crime Assistance (VOCA) grant 1989-93 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - W. K. Kellogg Foundation (Box 6)
      - General (Box 6)
        - 1987-88 (Box 6, Folder 22)
        - 1989-93 (Box 7, Folder 1-3)
      - Family/Community Cluster Network 1990 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      - Networking and Evaluation Conferences 1988-90 (Box 7, Folder 5-6)
  - Funding proposals, [see also SERIES VII. PROGRAMS]
    - ChoicesA Domestic Violence Shelter Assistance Program, undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Computer Program 1988 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Ihanktonwan Healthy Communities and Environment Program, circa 1997 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Melvin B. Bruguier Memorial Fast Pitch Tournament, undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Native American Women's Leadership Development Program for Improving Community Health, undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - NAWHERC pilot project general funding, circa 1988 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Rural Children and Community Computer and Internet Access Program, circa 1998 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - The Women's Lodge: A Domestic Violence Shelter Assistance Program, circa 1991 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Reference file: sample proposals 1989-91 (Box 7, Folder 15)
- SERIES V. LAKE ANDES WOMEN'S LODGE
  - General 1990-98, undated (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Emergency Proposal "A Call to Fight Racism and Assaults Against Native American Women," undated (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - High Street: abstracts of title to land 1942-87 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Zoning variance
    - Correspondence 1990-91 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Publicity 1990-91 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - NAWHERC vs. City of Lake Andes (Box 8)
      - Research and correspondence with Center for Constitutional Rights 1990-92, undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - Complaint, undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - Affirmations 1991 (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - Trial transcript, 2 Aug 1991; 6-7Aug 1991 (Box 8, Folder 5-7)
      - Judgement, 9 Aug 1991 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- SERIES VI. ORGANIZATIONS
  - Aboriginal Medical Services Alliance, Northern Territory, Australia (AMSANT) 1994-96, undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - American Civil Liberties Union, Reproductive Rights Update 1994-95 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - American Friends Service Committee 1985 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - American Indian Community House 1999 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - American Indian Health Care Association 1992 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - American Indian Organization, Winnebago 1986-92, undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Asian Pacific Islanders for Reproductive Health 1991-93, undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Black Hills Teton Sioux Nation 1995 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Bureau of Indian Affairs, [see United States Department of the Interior below]
    - Catholics for a Free Choice 1998 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Center for Cultural Survival, Inc. 1992 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Center for Reproductive Rights 2005 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - CHETNA, Gujarat, India 1993-94, undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Dakota Round Table
      - Dakota Roundtable I 1993 (Box 9)
        - General (Box 9, Folder 8)
        - Conference packet (Box 9, Folder 9)
        - Evaluations (Box 9, Folder 10)
          - A Report on the Status of Native American Youth in the Aberdeen Area (Box 9)
          - Draft (Box 9, Folder 11)
          - Published version (Box 9, Folder 12)
      - Dakota Roundtable II 1994 (Box 9)
        - A Report on the Status of Native American Women in the Aberdeen Area (Box 9)
        - Draft (Box 9, Folder 13)
        - Published version (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Dakota Roundtable III 1996 (Box 9)
      - General (Box 9, Folder 15)
      - A Report on the Status of Young Native American Women in the Aberdeen Area (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - DoCIP (Indigenous Peoples Center for Documentation, Research and Information) 1996-2004 (Box 9, Folder 17-18)
  - Federation of Feminist Women's Health Centers 1989-96 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Fond du Lac Group Home 1996 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Food and Drug Administration, [see United States Department of Health and Human Services below]
    - Four Worlds Development Project 1985-86 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Friends Committee on National Legislation 1998 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Greenpeace/National Coalition for Health and Environmental Justice 1995-97 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Grumin Indigenous Women Education Group 1996 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Indian Health Service, [see United States Department of Health and Human Services below]
      - Indian Land Working Group 2003 (Box 10, Folder 3)
      - Indian Youth of America 1989 (Box 10, Folder 4)
      - Indigenous Environmental Network 1991-96 (Box 10, Folder 5)
      - Interchange/Woman to Woman/Mujer a Mujer 1989, undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
      - International Women's Day Network 1991-92 (Box 10, Folder 7)
      - Lake Andes Indian Education Committee 1989 (Box 10, Folder 8)
      - Medical Students for Choice 1996 (Box 10, Folder 9)
      - Minnesota American Indian AIDS Task Force 1992-96 (Box 10, Folder 10)
      - Multicultural Women's Health Centre, Fremantle, Australia 1992 (Box 10, Folder 11)
      - Native Action 2001 (Box 10, Folder 12)
      - National Black Women's Health Project 1992-93, undated (Box 10, Folder 13)
      - National Coalition Against Domestic Violence 1998 (Box 10, Folder 14)
      - National Congress of American Indians 1997, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 15)
      - National Indian Health Board 1993 (Box 10, Folder 16)
      - National Latina Health Organization/Organizacion Nacional de la Salud de la Mujer Latina 1987-88, 1995 (Box 10, Folder 17)
      - National Native American AIDS Prevention Center 1989-91 (Box 10, Folder 18)
      - National Resource Center on Domestic Violence 1997-98 (Box 10, Folder 19)
      - National Rural Health Association 1988-89 (Box 10, Folder 20)
      - National SIDS and Infant Death Program Support Center 1999 (Box 10, Folder 21)
      - National Women's Health Network 1990-2005 (Box 10, Folder 22)
      - Native Indian Crisses Center, Blackfeet Reservation, undated (Box 10, Folder 23)
      - Native Women's Reproductive Rights Coalition, [see SERIES VII. PROGRAMS]
        - Oglala Lakota Nation 1994-96 (Box 10, Folder 24)
        - Peta Wakan Tipi 1994, undated (Box 10, Folder 25)
        - Planned Parenthood 1990-93 (Box 10, Folder 26)
        - Positively Native 1993-96 (Box 10, Folder 27)
        - Presbyterian Native American Caucus, undated (Box 10, Folder 28)
        - Religious Coalition for Abortion Rights, Women of Color Partnership Program 1988-91 (Box 11, Folder 1)
        - Sacred Fire Lodge, undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
        - SisterSong Women of Color Reproductive Health Collective
          - National Conference 2003 (Box 11, Folder 3)
          - Management Circle meetings (Box 11)
            - 9-10 Mar 2005 (Box 11, Folder 4)
            - Jul 2005 (Box 11, Folder 5)
          - Native Women's Reproductive Health and Rights Roundtable 2001 (Box 11, Folder 6)
        - South Dakota Advocacy Network for Women 1988-89 (Box 11, Folder 7)
        - South Dakota Coalition Against Domestic Violence
          - General 1987-89, 1993-96 (Box 11, Folder 8-9)
          - Calendar 1996 (Box 11, Folder 10)
        - South Dakota Legislative Task Force to Study Abortion 2005 (Box 11, Folder 11)
        - South Dakota Peace and Justice Center 1996 (Box 11, Folder 12)
        - Southeastern South Dakota Health Resources Development Program 1991-92 (Box 11, Folder 13)
        - Sustainable Native Agriculture Center (SNAC) 1988 (Box 11, Folder 14)
        - Trickle Up Program 1992-93 (Box 11, Folder 15)
        - United States Department of Health and Human Services
          - Miscellaneous departments 1989-2005 (Box 11, Folder 16)
          - Food and Drug Administration 1992-95 (Box 11, Folder 17)
          - Indian Health Service (Box 11)
            - General 1983-2006 (Box 11, Folder 18)
            - Budget: correspondence and notes 1989-90 (Box 12, Folder 1)
            - Correspondence 1988-93 (Box 12, Folder 2)
            - Indian Women's Health Care Round Table 1991 (Box 12, Folder 3)
            - Interviews with rape victims treated at IHS, Wagner 2003 (Box 12, Folder 4)
            - Proposed Wagner Service Unit closure: questions and concerns 1990 (Box 12, Folder 5)
            - Report: "Fiscal and Program Improvements Recommendations for Emergency Room Services, Yankton Wagner Service Unit" 2005 (Box 12, Folder 6)
            - Working Group on Native American women's reproductive health needs 2002-03, undated (Box 12, Folder 7-8)
        - United States Department of the Interior, Bureau of Indian Affairs 1992 (Box 12, Folder 9)
        - Venceremos Brigade 1988-89 (Box 12, Folder 10)
        - White Buffalo Calf Woman Society 1991 (Box 12, Folder 11)
        - White Mountain Apache Tribe 1989 (Box 12, Folder 12)
        - Women for a Meaningful Summit 1987/88 (Box 12, Folder 13)
        - Women for Racial and Economic Equality (WREE) 1988-94 (Box 12, Folder 14)
        - Women of All Red Nations (WARN) 1992 (Box 12, Folder 15)
        - Women's Global Network for Reproductive Rights 2000-03 (Box 12, Folder 16)
        - Women's International League for Peace and Freedom 1990-92 (Box 12, Folder 17)
        - Wyan Omni ?Ciye 1987 (Box 12, Folder 18)
        - Y-Me National Breast Cancer Organization 1994 (Box 12, Folder 19)
        - Yay Yukar no Mori 1995 (Box 12, Folder 20)
        - Young Women's Voices 1990 (Box 12, Folder 21)
        - Miscellaneous 1988-2005, undated (Box 12, Folder 22-23)
- SERIES VII. PROGRAMS
  - AIDS Prevention and Awareness
    - General1988, undated (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - "The Impact of AIDS in the Native American Community" by Tracey Easthope and Charon Asetoyer, summer 1988 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Proposals to foundations 1988-89 (Box 13)
      - Drafts and background materials (Box 13, Folder 3)
      - Proposal and correspondence 1988 (Box 13, Folder 4)
      - Proposal 1989 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - State of South Dakota contract, Jan 1989 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Public Health Service funding proposal, Jun 1989 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - South Dakota Native American AIDS Task Force/Coalition Planning Meeting, 9 Nov 1989 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Indian Health Service funding 1991-92 (Box 13)
      - Proposals, contracts, and notes (Box 13, Folder 9)
      - Evaluation reports (Box 13, Folder 10)
      - Notes on meetings with Donna Haukass, AIDS Consultant 1992 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - HIV/AIDS Training Conference for Young Adults, Mar 1992 (Box 13)
      - General (Box 13, Folder 12)
      - Training materials (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Reservation workshops 1992 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Second HIV/AIDS Gathering for Spiritual Leaders and Traditional Healers, 2-3 Jun 1992 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - HIV/AIDS Resource book: correspondence 1992 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Indian Health Service funding 1993-94 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Third HIV/AIDS Gathering for Spiritual Leaders and Traditional Healers, 11 Feb 1994 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Child Development Program
    - General 1988-93, undated (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - "A Program to Bridge the Educational Gaps for Native American Children," proposal submitted to the Yankton Sioux Tribe, Mar-Apr 1992 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Dakota Language and Culture Workbook and Coloring Book, Book I of the Dakota Cultural Institute 1994 (Box 13)
      - Draft (Box 13, Folder 21)
      - Published version (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Early Childhood Development/Dakota Language Immersion Program (aka Dakota Language Revitalization Program)
      - Support letters 2000 (Box 14, Folder 1)
      - Curriculum 2000-01 versions (Box 14, Folder 2)
      - Curriculum 2002 (Box 14, Folder 3)
      - Year 1 Process Evaluation Report, 20 Dec 2002 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Native American Language Revitalization and School Retention Program: proposal for Administration for Native Americans funding
      - Original, 16 Mar 2001 (Box 14, Folder 5)
      - Revisions, Jun-Jul 2001 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Dakota Language Advisory Committee 2002 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Colorectal Cancer Testing Campaign, Nov 1990 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Diabetes Awareness and Nutrition Program
    - General, undated (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - "The Positive Impact of Community Based Self-Help Education Among the Native American Diabetic Population of the Yankton Sioux Reservation" by Sonya Shin and Charon Asetoyer, summer 1991 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Domestic Violence Prevention Project
    - Proposal to U.S. Department of Justice 2002 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Findings of the Specialized Domestic Violence Probation Project 2005 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Fetal Alcohol Syndrome
    - Calendar and poster 1992 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Slide program: script, circa 1987, [see also SERIES I. GENERAL, HISTORY, AND PHOTOGRAPHS] (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Video: "Fetal Alcohol SyndromeA Global Issue," sales 1987-88 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Indigenous Women's Health Curriculum/Book
    - Curriculum, Feb 2000 (Box 15, Folder 1-3)
    - Curriculum, Jun 2001 (Box 15, Folder 4-6)
    - Book, revision 11, undated (Box 15, Folder 7-9)
    - Indigenous Women's Health Book, Within the Sacred Circle: Reproductive Rights, Environmental Health, Traditional Herbs and Remedies 2003 (Box 15)
      - Correspondence and notes 2000-03 (Box 15, Folder 10)
      - Draft, undated (Box 15, Folder 11-12)
      - Published book 2003 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Native American Community Health Education and Awareness Program, [see also W.K. Kellogg Foundation in SERIES IV. FINANCIAL MATERIALS]
    - Annual Report to Funders 1990-91 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Proposals 1988-92 (Box 16, Folder 3-6)
    - Proposal notes and background, undated (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Evaluation reports 1989-92 (Box 16, Folder 8-10)
  - Native American Women's Leadership Development Training Program, [see also W.K. Kellogg Foundation in SERIES IV. FINANCIAL MATERIALS]
    - General 1991-93, undated (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - "Expanding the Unfinished Agenda" on Health Issues Among Native Americans: proposal to the W.K. Kellogg Foundation (Box 16)
      - 19 Jun 1991 (Box 16, Folder 12)
      - Revised proposal 1992 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Advisory Committee (Box 16)
      - Membership 1993 (Box 16, Folder 14)
      - Minutes and reports 1993 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Evaluation report 1994 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Native American Young Peoples Wellness Program (NAYPWP)
    - General, undated (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Curriculum proposal 1995 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - "Curriculum of Workshops" 1999 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Family Violence Survey 2005 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - "Teen Dating Violence Support Group Curriculum" 1999 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - "Teen Dating Violence Prevention Curriculum and Workbook for Native American Girls" developed by Emily Janes, Mia Luluquisen, Kelly Hoffman, and Martina Taylor (Box 17)
      - Aug 2001 (Box 17, Folder 6)
      - Drafts 2001 (Box 17, Folder 7-9)
      - Questionnaires 2003 (Box 17, Folder 10)
      - Sales data 2002-03 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Statistics/data, undated (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Year Two Evaluation Report [page 1 missing] 1998 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Year Three Evaluation Report, Jul 2000 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Native Women's Reproductive Rights Coalition
    - General 1991 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Cervical cancer video survey 1991 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Funding 1991, undated (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Meetings 1990-93 (Box 18, Folder 4-8)
    - Conferences (Box 18)
      - Empowerment Through Dialogue: Native American Women and Reproductive Rights, 16-18 May 1990 (Box 18, Folder 9)
      - Native Women's Reproductive Rights Conference, 31 Jul 1990 (Box 18, Folder 10)
      - Second Native Women's Reproductive Rights Coalition Conference, 17-19 Jan 1993 (Box 18)
        - General (Box 18, Folder 11)
        - Daycare (Box 18, Folder 12)
        - Evaluations (Box 18, Folder 13)
        - Mailings (Box 18, Folder 14)
        - Speakers (Box 18, Folder 15)
      - Third Native Women's Reproductive Rights Coalition Conference 1994: planning materials (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Native Women's Reproductive Rights Agenda (developed at the Empowerment Through Dialogue conference 1990) (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Report on the Proposal Review, George Gund Foundation 1994 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Stop Smoking in Indian Country Campaign, 1993
    - General (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - Printed materials, [see also SERIES VIII. PUBLICATIONS and OVERSIZE MATERIALS] (Box 18, Folder 20)
    - Public Service Announcements 1993 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous 1989, 2005, undated (Box 18, Folder 22)
- SERIES VIII. PUBLICATIONS, [see also SERIES VII. PROGRAMS, and SERIES IX. STUDIES AND REPORTS]
  - Lists and order forms 2008-09, undated (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Brochures and fact sheets
    - NAWHERC general brochures, undated (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Cancer, undated (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Contraception, undated (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Contraception: research and drafts 1985-2005, undated (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Domestic Violence and Sexual Assault 1995, undated (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Environment, undated (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Fetal Alcohol Syndrome, undated (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Gay and Lesbian, undated (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Health, miscellaneous 1999, undated (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - HIV/AIDS 1992, undated (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Nutrition and Diabetes 1999, undated (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Reproductive Health and Pregnancy 1997, undated (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - Reproductive Health and Rights Agenda 1990, 2000 (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - Sexually Transmitted Diseases, undated (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - Smoking, undated (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - National Cancer Institute, US Department of Health and Human Services, Low Literacy Nutrition Education Materials Targeting Specific Underserved/Ethnic Populations, 1990-91
    - General, correspondence, and contract (Box 19, Folder 17-19)
    - Artwork by J.R. Rouse 1990 (Box 19, Folder 20)
    - "Healthy Choices on the Road" (Box 19, Folder 21)
    - "Less Fat is Easy" (Box 19, Folder 22)
    - "Traditional Food Can Be Healthy" (Box 19, Folder 23)
    - "Why All the Talk About Fiber?" (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - Wicozanni Wowapi Good Health Newsletter 1985-2004 (Box 19, Folder 25-26)
  - "Women's Reproductive Health and Rights" from NAWHERC Web site, circa 2005 (Box 19, Folder 27)
  - Newsletter notes and drafts, undated (Box 19, Folder 28)
- SERIES IX. STUDIES AND REPORTS
  - "Community Survey Report and Evaluation of the Native American Women's Health Education Resource Center Programs and Services" by Chelsea Harper, Nov 1997 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - "A Comprehensive Report on and Comparative Analysis of Methamphetamine Related Penalties in South Dakota and Other Midwestern States," Parul Garg, Bryony Heise, & Charon Asetoyer 2004 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - "Current Health Status of the Wagner Service Unit Area (Yankton, Santee and Rosebud Sioux Reservations) and the Effects of Indian Health Services Proposed Inpatient Service Closure," Raelene Walker 1989 (Box 20)
    - Report (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Research materials (Box 20, Folder 4-6)
  - "Current Status of the Wagner Indian Health Service Health Care Facility (Wagner, South Dakota) and the Effects of Indian Health Service's Inpatient Service Closure," Nicole Bazan 1994 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Dakota Round Table reports, [see SERIES VI. ORGANIZATION FILES]